<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>https://nau-datascience.github.io/</title>
   
   <link>https://nau-datascience.github.io/</link>
   <description>Academic Paper Summaries</description>
   <language>en-uk</language>
   
      
            
      
            
               
               
                  <managingEditor>Nadide Pasali</managingEditor>
            
      
            
      
   
   <title>
   <![CDATA[ Nadide Pasali - NAU-DataScience ]]>
   </title>
   <description>
   <![CDATA[ Academic Paper Summaries ]]>
   </description>
   <link>https://nau-datascience.github.io/</link>
   <image>
   <url>https://nau-datascience.github.io/assets/images/favicon.png</url>
   <title>Nadide Pasali - NAU-DataScience</title>
   <link>https://nau-datascience.github.io/</link>
   </image>
   <generator>Jekyll 3.6.2</generator>
   <lastBuildDate></lastBuildDate>
   <atom:link href="https://nau-datascience.github.io/author/nadide/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
   <ttl>60</ttl>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>Anomaly Detection</title>
	  <link>https://nau-datascience.github.io/Anomaly-Detection</link>
		
				
		
				
						<author>Nadide Pasali</author>
				
		
				
		
	  <pubDate>2018-01-27T02:00:00-06:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>https://nau-datascience.github.io/Anomaly-Detection</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p><a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/machine-learning/studio-module-reference/anomaly-detection">LINK</a></p>

<ul>
  <li>Rare events, finding unusual data points</li>
  <li>Encompasses many important tasks in ML
    <ul>
      <li>Identifying transactions that are potentially fraudulent</li>
      <li>Learning patterns that indicate a network intrusion has occurred</li>
      <li>Finding abnormal clusters of patients</li>
      <li>Checking values input to a system</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ul>

<h4 id="modules-for-an-anomaly-detection-model">Modules for an anomaly detection model</h4>
<ul>
  <li><a href="### One-Class Support Vector Machine">One-Class Support Vector Machine</a>: Creates a one-class Support Vector Machine model for anomaly detection, &gt;100features, aggressive boundary</li>
  <li><a href="### PCA-Based Anomaly Detection">PCA-Based Anomaly Detection</a>: Creates an anomaly detection model using Principal Component Analysis, Fast training</li>
</ul>

<hr />

<h3 id="one-class-support-vector-machine">One-Class Support Vector Machine</h3>

<p><a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/machine-learning/studio-module-reference/one-class-support-vector-machine">LINK</a></p>

<ul>
  <li>Particularly useful in scenarios where you have a lot of “normal” data and not many cases of the anomalies you are trying to detect (Ex: fraudulent transactions)</li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
  <p>Note: The module creates a kernel-SVM model, which means that it is not very scalable. If training time is limited, or you have too much data, you can use other methods such as PCA-Based Anomaly Detection.</p>
</blockquote>

<h4 id="understanding">Understanding</h4>

<ul>
  <li>Support vector machines (SVMs)
    <ul>
      <li>Supervised learning, used for both classification and regression tasks</li>
      <li>The SVM algorithm is given a set of training examples labeled as belonging to one of two classes</li>
      <li>Oversampling is used to replicate the existing samples so that you can create a two-class model, but it is impossible to predict all the new patterns of fraud or system faults from limited examples</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>Therefore, in <strong>one-class SVM</strong>, has only one class, which is the “normal” class</li>
  <li>From normal class properties can predict which examples are unlike the normal examples.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="configuration">Configuration</h4>

<ul>
  <li>η, represents the upper bound on the fraction of outliers (<a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/research/publication/estimating-the-support-of-a-high-dimensional-distribution/?from=http%3A%2F%2Fresearch.microsoft.com%2Fpubs%2F69731%2Ftr-99-87.pdf">nu-property</a>)
    <ul>
      <li>lets you control the trade-off between outliers and normal cases</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>ε (epsilon), value to use as the stopping tolerance.
    <ul>
      <li>affects the number of iterations used when optimizing the model, and depends on the stopping criterion value</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ul>

<p><em>Single Parameter</em>, a specific set of values as arguments<br />
 <em>Parameter Range</em>, specifying multiple values and using a parameter sweep to find the optimal configuration</p>

<hr />

<h3 id="pca-based-anomaly-detection">PCA-Based Anomaly Detection</h3>

<p><a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/machine-learning/studio-module-reference/pca-based-anomaly-detection">LINK</a></p>

<ul>
  <li>Use in scenarios where it is easy to obtain training data from one class, such as valid transactions, but difficult to obtain sufficient samples of the targeted anomalies.</li>
  <li>By using the PCA-Based Anomaly Detection module, you can train the model using the available features to determine what constitutes a “normal” class, and then use distance metrics to identify cases that represent anomalies.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="understanding-1">Understanding</h4>

<ul>
  <li>Principal Component Analysis (PCA)
    <ul>
      <li>ML technique can be applied to feature selection and classification</li>
      <li>Used in exploratory data analysis, reveals the inner structure of the data and explains the variance in the data</li>
      <li>Analyze data that contains multiple variables, all possibly correlated, and determine some combination of values that best captures the differences in outcomes. Then outputs the combination of values into a new set of values called <em>principal components</em>.</li>
      <li>In the case of <strong>anomaly detection</strong>,
        <ul>
          <li>First computes projection on the eigenvectors, then computes the normalized reconstruction error.</li>
          <li>This normalized error is the anomaly score.</li>
          <li>The higher the error, the more anomalous the instance is.</li>
        </ul>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ul>

<h4 id="configuration-1">Configuration</h4>

<ul>
  <li>Number of components to use in PCA (or Range)
    <ul>
      <li>The decision of how many components to include is an important part of experiment design using PCA</li>
      <li>Should not include the same number of PCA components as there are variables. Start with some smaller number of components and increase them until some criteria is met
        <ul>
          <li>If you are unsure of what the optimum value, use parameter range</li>
          <li>If you manually specify a value, make sure that the number of output components is less than the number of feature columns available in the dataset.</li>
        </ul>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>Amount of oversampling
    <ul>
      <li>A single integer that represents the ratio of oversampling of the minority class over the normal class (series of interger, range)</li>
      <li>Imbalanced data makes it difficult to apply standard PCA techniques. By specifying some amount of oversampling, you can increase the number of target instances.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
  <p>If you specify 1, no oversampling is performed.
If you specify any value higher than 1, additional samples are  generated to use in training the model.
However, you cannot view the oversampled data set.</p>
</blockquote>

<ul>
  <li>Enable input feature mean normalization, to normalize all input features to a mean of zero</li>
  <li>Normalization or scaling to zero is generally recommended for PCA, because the goal of PCA is to maximize variance among variables.</li>
  <li>Some additional steps
    <ul>
      <li>Ensure that a score column is available in both datasets</li>
      <li>Ensure that label columns are marked</li>
      <li>Normalize scores from different model types</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ul>


	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
